Same Land. Same God. Different Dreams.
Gettysburg is a drama, history, war film directed by Ronald F. Maxwell.
In the summer of 1863, General Robert E.
Lee leads the Confederate Army of Northern Virginia into Gettysburg,
Pennsylvania with the goal of marching through to Washington, D.C.
The Union Army of the Potomac, under the command of General George G.
Meade, forms a defensive position to confront the rebel forces in what will
prove to be the decisive battle of the American Civil War.
Col. Joshua Chamberlain, played by Jeff Daniels.
Lieut. Gen. James Longstreet, played by Tom Berenger.
Gen. Robert E. Lee, played by Martin Sheen.
Brig. Gen. John Buford, played by Sam Elliott.
Maj. Gen. George E. Pickett, played by Stephen Lang.
Lieut. Thomas D. Chamberlain, played by C. Thomas Howell.
Gettysburg is a 1993 American epic war film about the
Battle of Gettysburg in the American Civil War.
Written and directed by Ronald F.
Maxwell, the film was adapted from the 1974 historical
novel The Killer Angels by Michael Shaara.
It features an ensemble cast, including Tom Berenger as James Longstreet,
Jeff Daniels as Joshua Chamberlain, Martin Sheen as Robert E.
Lee, Stephen Lang as George Pickett, and Sam Elliott as John Buford.
Originally filmed as a miniseries for TNT, Gettysburg received a limited theatrical release
from New Line Cinema under the direction of Ted Turner, who owned both entities.
At four hours and 14 minutes, it is the longest film released
theatrically by a major film studio in the United States.
It received positive reviews from critics and despite grossing $12.7 million on a $20 million budget
was considered a hit due to its successful TNT premiere ratings and home video sales.
A prequel entitled Gods and Generals was released in 2003, also directed
by Maxwell and featuring many returning cast members.
The film explores themes of army, civil war,
independence, troops, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.